Narrator: 4
Idioms and expressions with measurements
Narrator: 1
F: Sam thought he’d get away with not doing his coursework,
but his tutor came down on him like a ton of bricks.
Narrator: 2
M: When the tanker sank, gallons of oil washed ashore and thousands of seabirds died.
Narrator: 3
M: Whatever you do, don’t mention moving in together on your first date, or she’ll run a mile.
Narrator: 4
F: Can you give me a hand with this huge box? It weighs a ton.
Narrator: 5
M: Fiona’s so conscientious. She’ll always go the extra mile to complete a project on time.
Narrator: 6
F: I had a narrow escape this morning
– a great chunk fell off the cliff as I was walking on the beach. It missed me by inches!
Narrator: 7
A: I lent him my bike just for the weekend, and two weeks later, I still haven’t got it back!
B: I did warn you! Give him an inch and he’ll take a mile.
Narrator: 8
M: We’re going to be really late
– it’s 11.30 already and thanks to that accident on the motorway, we’re still miles away.
Narrator: 9
F: I know he promised you half the house, but I wouldn’t trust him an inch, if I were you.
Narrator: 10
M: On my first day in the job, I wore a suit, but I stood out a mile
– everyone else was in jeans and T- shirts.